<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Courses | eduquant</title><link>/courses/</link><atom:link href="/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Courses</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Pieter van den Berg</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/media/logo.png</url><title>Courses</title><link>/courses/</link></image><item><title>Credit Risk Model Development</title><link>/courses/credit-risk-model-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/courses/credit-risk-model-development/</guid><description>
&lt;a href="/#contact" target="_blank" class="btn btn-primary">
&lt;i class="fa fa-download">&lt;/i>
Apply Now
&lt;/a>
&lt;h2 id="content">Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="learning-goals">Learning Goals&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="target-audience">Target Audience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course is intended for&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>IRB model developers with little or no prior experience in the field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Specialist supervisors wishing to gain insight in internal model developer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Prior basic knowledge of statistical testing and modeling is strongly advised. Some experience in programming with &lt;code>python&lt;/code> or a statistcal computing language may be helpful for the case studies, but is not required.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="format">Format&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course will be taught through a combination of&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>lectures (online and offline)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ongoing, interactive quizzes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>break-out sessions with challenging case studies and hands-on workshops&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="date-and-duration">Date and duration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This course will take place over the course of 4 days in February, 2021.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Credit Risk Model Validation</title><link>/courses/credit-risk-model-validation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/courses/credit-risk-model-validation/</guid><description>
&lt;a href="/#contact" target="_blank" class="btn btn-primary">
&lt;i class="fa fa-download">&lt;/i>
Apply Now
&lt;/a>
&lt;h2 id="content">Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Model validation, the independent and effective challenge of risk model development, is a cornerstone of model risk control at larger and more mature financial institutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The model validator must learn to question the credit risk model parameters, audit the decision making process and understand the trade-offs of the resulting model design choices. They need to understand the broader context of their inquiries and translate these into a sound advice to executive management. In addition, they need to understand regulation and internal policies, and the expectations of supervisors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this course, participants learn how to validate credit risk models in the context of the CRR and underlying regulatory technical standards and guidelines, as well as supervisory expectations. Statistical foundations of model validation will be explained in combination with practical guidance for applying these. Attention will also be given to validating documentation and more technical aspects of verifying the correctness and reproducibility results. The knowledge will be acquired through several real-life case studies and exercises.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The exact course contents are adapted based on a survey under participants 4-6 weeks before start of the course.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="learning-goals">Learning Goals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing the course, participants will&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>be able to find, understand and interpret regulatory requirements for banks using internal models, and translate these into specific assessments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>know and reflect on the role and responsibilities of the model validation function within the bank&lt;/li>
&lt;li>learn to question decision making processes and verify the reproducibility and correctness of results&lt;/li>
&lt;li>understand and use procedures for statistical testing, benchmarking and the use of challenger models&lt;/li>
&lt;li>learn to use specific statistical tests to challenge key decisions in modelling probability of default (PD), loss given default (LGD), and exposure at default (EAD) models&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="target-audience">Target Audience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course is intended for&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>IRB model validators with little or no prior experience in the field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Specialist supervisors wishing to gain insight in internal model validation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Prior basic knowledge of statistical testing and modeling is strongly advised. Some experience in programming with &lt;code>python&lt;/code> or a statistcal computing language may be helpful for the case studies, but is not required.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="format">Format&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course will be taught through a combination of&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>lectures (online and offline)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ongoing, interactive quizzes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>break-out sessions with challenging case studies and hands-on workshops&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="date-and-duration">Date and duration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This course will take place over the course of 4 days in February, 2021.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downturn LGD &amp; CCF</title><link>/courses/downturn-lgd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/courses/downturn-lgd/</guid><description>
&lt;a href="/#contact" target="_blank" class="btn btn-primary">
&lt;i class="fa fa-download">&lt;/i>
Apply Now
&lt;/a>
&lt;h2 id="content">Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>History has witnessed severe economic crises with an impact on financial institutions worldwide. Examples are the Asian Financial Crisis, Dot.com bubble, Global Financial Crisis, Sovereign Debt Crisis and the COVID-19 pandemic. The European Capital requirements regulation (CRR) requires financial institutions that adopt the Advanced Internal Ratings Based Approach (A-IRB) models to use Loss Given Default (LGD) estimates that are appropriate for an economic downturn if those are more conservative than the long-run average LGD. A similar requirement is imposed by the regulation for Credit Conversion Factors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This deep-dive course provides context of regulatory requirements for identifying economic downturn periods and of those for estimating the downturn LGD and CCF risk parameters. Key challenges met by model developers when applying the regulatory requirements concerning economic downturn are treated in detail, for example&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>When are economic indicators deemed relevant for identifying an economic downturn?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How should one determine what is considered to be an economic downturn period?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Which of the approaches identified in regulation should be followed for quantifying Downturn LGDs?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can the volatility of capital requirements be limited if LGD estimates are sensitive to economic conditions?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How should the downturn LGD for in-default exposures be modelled and what is the relation to the EL$_{\text{BE}}$?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What are the main drivers of model risk for Downturn LGD and CCF estimates, and which Margin of Conservatism items should be considered for Downturn quantification purposes?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The exact course contents are adapted based on a survey under participants 4-6 weeks before start of the course.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="learning-goals">Learning Goals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing the course, the participants will be able to identify downturn periods by gaining knowledge on the following topics:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Selection of relevant economic indicators&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Considerations with regard to geography and sectors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Choice of historical period, frequency of the data and implications&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Guidance for transformations of economic indicators&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Co-movement of economic indicators&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identification of adjacent peaks and troughs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pitfalls in the downturn period identification&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Furthermore, participants will be able to quantify Downturn LGD by gaining knowledge on the following topics:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Three main Downturn quantification approaches:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Type 1 - Observed impact approach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Type 2 - Extrapolation/haircut approach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Type 3 - Flexible approach with minimum add-ons&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Treatment of incomplete recovery cases in Downturn estimates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Accounting for LGD estimates that are unduly sensitive to the economic cycle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Backtesting Downturn estimates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regulatory challenger model&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Choosing a final relevant Downturn period&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When to use Downturn LGD estimates in the calculation of capital requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pitfalls in the downturn LGD quantification&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Participants will also gain knowledge of the following topics:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Margin of Conservatism for Downturn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Quantification of Downturn CCF&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Key process steps in Downturn quantification&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Focus points during Model Validation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Relation between Downturn requirements and related requirements for LGD and PD.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="target-audience">Target Audience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course is intended for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>IRB model developers and team leads with a specific interest in economic downturn IRB modelling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Model validators and team leads with similar interests.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supervisors and policy advisors wishing to gain insight in the challenges of applying regulation with regard to economic downturn.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Credit risk managers wishing to enhance their understanding of Downturn LGD modelling&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Participants are advised to come equipped with aasic understanding of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the calculation of capital requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>relevant regulation for A-IRB&lt;/li>
&lt;li>modelling the LGD and EAD/CCF risk parameters.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="format">Format&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course will be taught through a combination of&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>challenging case studies and interactive workshops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>lectures (online and offline)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ongoing, interactive quizzes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="date-and-duration">Date and duration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This course will take place over the course of 3 days in February, 2021.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Low-default portfolios</title><link>/courses/low-default-portfolios/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/courses/low-default-portfolios/</guid><description>
&lt;a href="/#contact" target="_blank" class="btn btn-primary">
&lt;i class="fa fa-download">&lt;/i>
Apply Now
&lt;/a>
&lt;h2 id="content">Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Applying internal ratings based approaches for low-default portfolios comes with a specific set of additional challenges, because of the nature of the obligors, type of lending activities, complexity of recovery processes and credit risk cyclicality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Typical challenges, which will be discussed during the course, are&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>estimating PDs, cyclicality adjustments and MoC values where the number and rate of defaults is low or zero&lt;/li>
&lt;li>dealing with material sources of uncertainty and the estimation of a margin of conservatism&lt;/li>
&lt;li>demonstrating compliance where both in the rating assignment process and model design and estimation there is a dominating reliance on expert judgement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>identification of an economic downturn for globally distributed portfolios or exposures across industry sectors&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The term &lt;em>low-default portfolio&lt;/em> typically denotes credit exposures to large corporates, financial institutions and sovereigns, but these issues can be relevant for other types of exposures as well, for example&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>specialized lending and project finance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>low-risk niche lending activities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>smaller portfolios&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The exact course contents are adapted based on a survey under participants 4-6 weeks before start of the course.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="learning-goals">Learning Goals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing the course, participants will&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>be familiar with the specific challenges in modelling and validating minimum capital requirements for &lt;strong>low-default portfolio&lt;/strong> rating systems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>know the specific &lt;strong>regulatory requirements&lt;/strong> relevant for these rating systems, in particular for expert-based models, shadow rating models and models covering global portfolios&lt;/li>
&lt;li>be able to identify and challenge &lt;strong>key decisions&lt;/strong> in the IRB modelling process for these portfolios&lt;/li>
&lt;li>understand the &lt;strong>view of the regulator and supervisory expectations&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>have a broad view of the impact of &lt;strong>new regulation&lt;/strong> and Basel IV on these portfolios&lt;/li>
&lt;li>grasp the concepts of and requirements for &lt;strong>specific modelling techniques&lt;/strong> (for example, use of external data, Bayesian inference, Pluto-Tasche) and know how to apply and challenge these&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="target-audience">Target Audience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course is intended for&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>IRB model developers and team leads with a specific interest in low-default portfolio IRB models&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Model validators and team leads with similar interests&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supervisors and policy advisors wishing to gain insight in the challenges of applying regulation for LDP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Credit risk managers wishing to enhance their understanding of IRB modelling for LDP&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Participants are advised to come equipped with a broad understanding of credit risk modelling and IRB regulation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="format">Format&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course will be taught through a combination of&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>challenging case studies and interactive workshops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>lectures (online and offline)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ongoing, interactive quizzes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="date-and-duration">Date and duration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This course will take place over the course of 3 days in February, 2021.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Margin of Conservatism</title><link>/courses/moc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/courses/moc/</guid><description>
&lt;a href="/#contact" target="_blank" class="btn btn-primary">
&lt;i class="fa fa-download">&lt;/i>
Apply Now
&lt;/a>
&lt;h2 id="content">Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Basel concept of a Margin of Conservatism, implemented and further refined in the EBA Guidelines to PD and LGD estimation, manifest the fundamental idea that model risk &lt;em>is&lt;/em> credit risk, and should be capitalized for accordingly. The European Capital Requirements Regulation prescribes that institutions should add to its risk parameters estimates a Margin of Conservatism (MoC) which reflects uncertainties in the estimated risk parameters. These uncertainties should be calculated based on a comprehensive process to identify and quantify deficiencies in risk parameter estimation. Biases should be addressed by so-called appropriate adjustments and the MoC should also reflect the uncertainties on these adjustments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While perhaps conceptually straightforward, the implementation of these regulatory requirements and guidelines is seen as one of the more challenging aspects of implementing IRB. Firstly, because of the complex nature of the requirements and underlying concepts, and secondly, because of the practical difficulties in connecting the theoretical basis and regulation to the practical reality of risk model development and validation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This advanced course brings to model developers and model validators a thorough understanding of the statistical and conceptual basis of Margin of Conservatism and the applicable regulation, as well as the mental machinery to help bring these into practice. Through challenging hands-on case studies, interactive lectures and stimulating discourse, participants will gain experience with, among others, the following topics&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Integration of a conceptual and statistical basis of the Margin of Conservatism with regulatory terminology and supervisory expectations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Setup, verification and challenge of a process for the identication, quantification and validation of model deficiencies and uncertainties&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Expected key elements of a Margin of Conservatism framework&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Approaches for deriving appropriate adjustments and MoC factors for typical sources of bias and uncertainty, such as
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>a lack of data quality, completeness or representativeness&lt;/li>
&lt;li>limitations to the method of quantification of risk parameters&lt;/li>
&lt;li>changes to default- and loss definitions, underwriting standards, collection and recovery policies, or business environments&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understanding the general estimation error&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aggregation of the Margin of Conservatism to the risk parameter level, including Downturn LGD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Requirements for the use of human judgment&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The exact course contents are adapted based on a survey under participants 4-6 weeks before start of the course.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="learning-goals">Learning Goals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing the course, the participants will be able to&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Quantify the Margin of Conservatism for typical sources of bias and uncertainty in credit risk modelling&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Challenge and verify the completeness, correctness and compliance of a MoC derivation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set up a process and recognize key decisions for the identification of deficiencies and uncertainties in the data and methodology&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand trade-offs between different approaches in terms of complexity, explainability, and conservatism&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="target-audience">Target Audience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course is intended for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>IRB model developers and team leads with a specific interest in determining appropriate adjustments and a Margin of Conservatism for the PD, LGD and EAD/CCF risk parameters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Model validators, Auditors and team leads with similar interests.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supervisors and policy advisors wishing to gain insight in the challenges of regulation with regard to the Margin of Conservatism.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Model Owners and Credit Risk Controllers wishing to enhance their understanding of the Margin of Conservatism&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Participants are advised to come equipped with a basic understanding of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the calculation of minimum capital requirements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>modelling the PD, LGD and EAD/CCF risk parameters.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="format">Format&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course will be taught through a combination of&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>challenging case studies and interactive workshops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>lectures (online and offline)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ongoing, interactive quizzes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="date-and-duration">Date and duration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This course will take place over the course of 3 days in February, 2021.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>